do you know anyone who died?
а у вас кто-то из знакомых есть погибших
Well, look in St. Petersburg, it’s like here, I don’t
Ну смотрите в Питере как бы тут я не
know, there’s no such excitement about the dead,
знаю тут нет такого ажиотажа по погибшим
I’m from a small town, it’s clear that
я вот из маленького Городка понятное
everyone there is there, well,
дело то что там вообще там каждый там ну
every week this cargo of 200 arrives in
каждую неделю этот груз 200 приезжает в
St. Petersburg for everyone  I don’t care, it’s like, a neighbor died
Питере всем пофиг Да там типа сосед умер
and no one knew. Yes, it’s true. And there, it’s like
никто и не знал Да правда А там как бы
we’re like a big family. Every week in this gut there
мы как семья большая Вот в этой гуте
was someone who died. Cruz
каждую неделю был кто-то погибший Круз
200 Yes, a steady number of young guys come,
200 Да приезжает стабильно молодые парни
someone Well  someone is dying from Drones and
кто-то Ну кто-то вот от Дронов умирает а
what is the population in your city
сколько у вас население в городе
26,000 26,000 and every week someone is
26.000 26.000 и каждую неделю кто-то
killed Hello Hello,
погибший Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вам
my heart, where are you
сердечко Вы
from? Well, I know that Russia yes
откуда Ну я знаю что Россия да Город
What city is Peter Peter Peter Cool yes I come
какой Питер Питер Прикольно да я родом
from I come from Vyborg But I live  in London
из я родом из Выборга Но живу в Лондоне
18 years in 2 years will be 20
18 лет через 2 года будет двадцатом
[music]
[музыка]
hasn’t been back in 18 years in Russia so it’s
не вернулся за 18 лет в России значит
cool in London after all  who are you
всё-таки в Лондоне круто вы на кого
studying to be a pharmacist in St. Petersburg and where are you from?
учитесь в Питере фармацевт а сами откуда
I’m from Yakutia, I’m from here from Pite from
родом я с Якутии я отсюда из Пите из
Sakha Yes, I’m Sakha Yes, my father is from Yakutia
саха Да я Саха Да у меня отец э с Якутии
We know the Aldan
Мы же знаете там алданское
deposit there Well Aldan Yes I know Yes,
месторождение Ну Алдан Да я знаю Да вот
he was born there, his grandfather also worked
он там родился у него дед тоже работал
in the Golden Mines, like, and my father came here to
на Золотых Рудниках типа а отец приехал
study here during the Soviet Union. Well, he was in Leningrad
при Союзе учиться сюда в Ну в Ленинград
when he was there and met my
ещё когда был и познакомился с моей
mother. I was born here. And they lived in Vyborg, it’s
мамой Я тут родился Да и в Выборге они
cool Aldan he  in my opinion,
жили прикольно Алдан он по-моему
more Well, this is Sakha Yakutia anyway, yes
более Ну это Саха Якутия всё равно да
dadada, of course yes Well, it’s not near Yakutsk
дадада конечно да Ну он не возле Якутска
Yes, it’s further away And where am
Да там подальше А вы
I from? I’m from St. Petersburg and I understood And you
откуда я я из Питера понял А вы на
decided on pharmacists Why did you decide on
фармацевтов Почему решили именно на
pharmacists Yes, my grandmother, a pharmacist,
фармацевтов Да у меня бабушка провизор
understood Not but you want  then go back
понял Не а вы вы хотите потом вернуться
to Sakha, no Where can you live here in St. Petersburg and you’re
в Саха нет А куда тут в Питере жить а вы
Russian Sakha I’m Russian Russian Russian
русская Саха Я русская русская русская
Ponya And how they treat Russians in Sakha
Поня А как там в Саха к русским
I heard that Well, well, they’re
относятся Я слышал что Ну так Ну они же
tough nationalists Well  well, as if in
жёсткие националисты Ну вот ну как бы в
principle it is not felt, but in
принципе это не чувствуется Но вот в
terms of work, perhaps if somewhere the
плане работы Возможно если где-то больше
Yakuts predominate, then yes you and in the World Cup
преобладают якуты то да тебя а в ч в ЧМ
What is the nationalism of the Yakuts that
В чём национализм у якутов вот
is expressed in them, firstly, their self-esteem
выражается у них во-первых самооценка
is inflated, they are me, and only  I, yes, they are
завышенная они вот я Я и только я да они
very well, inflated self-esteem, for example,
очень ну завышенная самооценка например
well, they are the coolest there. They
ну что они там самые крутые Всё круто
do everything cool, they know Russians, Russians
делают всё знают русские русские там
can only buy there and all that. I
только могут вот купить и всё такое Я
know that I lived in Vyborg. We have
знаю что вот я жил в Выборге У нас вот
Russians here.  they lived there alone and they had
русские там одни жили да и у них было
something like that, that’s all of us. In short, the whole of
такое что вот мы всё Мы короче вся
America Finland Germany We are Russians
Америка Финляндия Германия Мы русские
That’s what the Russians had And what do the
Вот то это такое у русских было А что у
Yakuts like have the same thing, yes, the Yakuts
якутов типа есть тоже таше да у якутов
have it, yes I understood that, yes Well, the Russians here
есть да такое понял да Ну русский тут
Everyone is for himself  They themselves are Yakuts, they’re just the
Каждый сам за себя якуты они прямо вот
whole crowd for each other That’s it and
вся толпа за друг друга Вот так вот и
that’s why because I looked at the
поэтому потому что я смотрел перепись
population census Yes, the modern Yakuts are already
населения Да современную уже якутов
80% in my opinion Yes in the Republic of Sakha Because
по-моему 80% Да в Республике Саха Потому
during the Union it was 50%  there Lenin Stalin is
что при Союзе было 50% там Ленин Сталина
not
не
a bunch of Russians leaving, that’s how you are Yes, that’s how it
куча русских уезжает вот как вы Да так
turns out And they abandon this Republic
получается И бросают эту Республику
so that it remains again Yakut, they will
чтобы она оставалась снова Якутская они
then take independence and proclaim
потом возьмут независимость провозгласят
No, it’s unlikely that Why when they become
Нет навряд ли та Почему когда их станет
there, well, there will be almost no Russians left Well,
там ну русских почти не останется Ну так
they will be disturbed a lot but
что им будет мешать очень много но
Now there are a lot of Tajiks and Kyrgyz there.
сейчас там и таджиков много и киргизов
Well, here are the Tajiks and the Kyrgyz. Yes, and the Yakuts
Ну вот таджики с киргизами Да и якута
will be short-lived, and that’s all, and where will the Russian city be?
проведут да и всё и где будет русский
St. Petersburg Well, St. Petersburg, and
санкт-петербург Ну так санкт-петербург а
my mother lives there with my dad, there are already
у меня ж мама там живёт с папой там уже
Uzbeks, Tajiks, everything there is no longer
узбеки таджики всё там уже не
Russian Well, there are a lot of Chinese here,
русский Ну да тут китайцев много
the city is no longer in Russia,
русского города уже в России не осталось
everything is unfortunately all mixed up Yes,
всё к сожалению всё перемешалось Да
yes, there is this problem Yes  And what do
Да есть эта проблемка Да А вы получается
you guys get? What Russians are not Russians Russians,
у Вас парни Какие русские не русские
but why was my girlfriend so hesitant?
а что так замялась подружка у подружки
My girlfriend is not Russian, I
не русский у меня парня
don’t have a boyfriend, so he will be Not Russian,
нет значит будет Не русский
yeah, well  a Slav would be desirable there, no
да ну славянин бы желательно там без
matter whether he’s Russian or not, I don’t
разницы русский он или там не
know what’s what. And for example, for a
знаю а что а что сло А например там за
Kazakh or for a Yakut, like a
казаха или за якута типа менталитет
different mentality, what, what a different mentality,
другой что что менталитет другой
well, How can I
какой ну
say it’s more harsh on
Как сказать там более жёстко к
girls like you have to do this? Well, for example, for
девушкам типа ты должна это Ну например
example Karel Yes
например Карел Да
there will be a guy from Karelia Karel, you should
вот из Карелии будет парень Карел ты бы
date him Well, he’s not a
с ним встречалась Ну да так он же не
Slav I don’t know how to say this No,
славянин Я не знаю как это сказать Нет
most likely you’re a
скорее всего ты
proto-people, I would
прой народ я говор бы
n’t say it, for example  Tatar legend I
нехо вот например татарин сказание там с
dated a Tatar there for 2 years and
татарином встречалась 2 с по года и
that's why I say what happened Well,
что Поэтому я и говорю а что что было Ну
he was a bit harsh towards me Well, these are
он жестковато ко мне Ну это же
Muslims, so I know, Russian guys,
мусульмане так я знаю вот русские парни
he was generally tough there, he beat his wife for
он там вообще жёстко был там свою жену
something He didn't like it  Well, he’s
побил что-то Ему не понравилось Ну
also Russian. So look at the news, a Russian
русский ещё Так посмотри новости русский
beat his wife, and so on, it’s also
побил жену жену и так дальше тоже
clear, yes, it depends on the person. Well,
понятно да это от человека зависит Ну
it’s clear that, first of all, it depends on the
это понятно что в первую очередь от
person, on his
человека от его
society, on his habits and the
общества вот от его привычек и тому
like, but often it turns out that
подобное но зачастую так получается что
somehow  It doesn’t work out
как-то не складывается
with
с
Muslims, I
мусульманами
understand that they have different customs The faith is different,
понял да у них другие обычаи Вера другая
everything is different with them Yes Cool And what
всё другое у них Да Прикольно А вы какой
faith are you? Christianity is right Name the 10
веры христианство право Назовите 10
commandments and I won’t name the 10 commandments there,
заповедей а не назову 10 заповедей там
don’t kill
не убивать
m Don’t steal, don’t steal, don’t
м Не воровать не воровать не
betray No, I don’t know Well, at least three
предавать Нет я не знаю Ну хотя бы три
Call it don't kill like that don't don't steal like that
Назовите не убий так не Не воровать так
don't Steal it from yours or something like
не Укради него своего или что-то такое
that don't betray like that no no
что-что не предавать такого нету нет
like that I don't know the truth I I can't  to
так нут Я не знаю правда Я я не могу
say that I am some kind of myself this is to
сказать то что я какой-то себя это
Faith there was like no They are with people from
Вере там было типа нет Они с людьми из
another
другого
nation and what is your Christianity then
народа а в чём ваше христианство тогда
if you don’t even know 10 I
заключается если вы не знаете даже 10 я
I No I I I am not attached to
я Нет я я я не привязана ни к какому ни
any Faith And
какой Вере А
girlfriend I  I read
подружка Я читала
VST for me it’s a tool for
вст для меня это ВС инструмент
managing people Well, if this makes it easy for someone, then
управления людьми Ну если кому-то легко
Well, someone
от этого то Ну ктото
believe such an interesting question What do you
вери такой интересный вопрос А как вы
think? Yes, there is now a war in Ukraine
считаете Да идт сейчас война в Украине
and Russia and Ukraine, why did it
да Россия с Украиной из-за чего она
start if we  they knew it
началась если бы мы знали
themselves I don’t know either, they don’t report it, but
сами Я тоже не знаю не докладывают но
I’m thinking about it
я-то размышляю
Here’s your version Well, there is a version Yes,
Вот ваше версии Ну есть версия Да
damn, well, initially, since the fourteenth
блин ну изначально же с четырнадцатого
year, the extermination of the Russian people,
года истребление русского народа
Ukraine Donbass was divided into two
поделилась Украина Донбасс на две
parts. Our Volodya was fed up with this and he
части Володю нашего это достало и он
decided to say, well, that’s enough and he led the troops and
решил сказал ну хватит и вёл войска а
who is to blame for all this
кто виноват в этом
Bandera is correct, that’s good, what do you
Бандера правильно вот это хорошо что вы
know, but in
знаете а
general, initially, as I know from history,
вообще изначально как я знаю по истории
that Bandera was during the Second
что Бандера же это в период Второй
World War, he was this, this is another
мировой войны он был это это другой
Bandera. Is there also  Bandera who
Бандера А есть же ещё Бандера который на
attacked the Donbass is his modern grandson, well,
Донбасс напал современный его внук ну
it’s just, well, he’s like, well, you can say
просто ну он же как бы ну можно сказать
the son of this or not the grandson of the grandson Well, yes, but the point
сын того или нет внук внук Ну да Но суть
is that Bandera was initially imprisoned in the
в том что изначально посадили бандеру во
Second World War and then someone I really do
Вторую Мировую а потом кто-то я правда
n’t know, I don’t know the history well, then  either Yeltsin
не знаю плохо историю знаю то ли Ельцин
or someone. Of these new ones, he
то ли кто-то Вот из этих вот новых
released a gang of
выпустил банде
them to America. They went to America and
их в Америку они уехали в Америку и
then maybe they somehow went to Ukraine. And
потом может как-то они на Украину Да и
his grandson is like his grandson. This is what it
внук его типа внук его вот это А какое
was like. Maybe you know on TV
было Вот Может вы знаете по телевизору
they showed that  did  Bandera on the Maidan
показывали что делал Бандера на Майдане
in 1414 Honestly, I don’t even know Well, for
в 14м году Честно я даже не знаю Ну ну
some reason Bandera attacked the
Бандера ж почему-то напал на
Donbass I don’t know that either, maybe
Донбасс Вот этого я тоже не знаю может
because people wanted to
из-за того что ему люди хотели
disconnect from him Well yes, yes, people
отсоединиться Ну да лю Да люди люди
wanted to disconnect Yes, who Let’s
хотели отсоединиться Да а кто Давайте
So  who, together with Bandero, seized power
Так кто вместе с бандеро захватил власть
on the
на
Maidan? I honestly don’t know these
Майдане Я честно не знаю вот этих вот
moments. Petlyura Bandera and Petlyura
моментов Петлюра Бандера и Петлюра
seized power on the Maidan in 2014,
захватили власть на Майдане в 2014 году
and Petlyura said that  Donbass needs to
да и Петлюра говорил что донбассу нужно
be given autonomy, and what did Bandera say that
дать автономию а Бандера что сказал что
he doesn’t need to be given autonomy, doesn’t need to be
ему не нужно дать автономию не нужно
given autonomy? What did the people of Donbass do? They
дать автономию Да что сделали люди
started fighting against the gang
Донбасса начали воевать против банде
against Bandera, that’s right, where the most
против Бандеры правильно где самая
famous battle of the people of Donbass with
известная битва народа Донбасса с
Bandera took place where I’m not honest Well, in the
бандеро произошла где я не честно Ну на
Donbass somewhere Well  correct And
Донбассе где-то Ну правильно А
where Donetsk Lugansk is not the village of Old
где Донецк Луганск не там село Старый
Ugrinov we will
угринов будем
know the LPR and DPR entered into battle with the
знать лнр и ДНР вступили в бой с
united united army of Bandera
объединённый объединённой армией Бандеры
And even then Bandera completely defeated the army of
А и тогда Бандера разбил полностью армию
the DPR LPR, she began to retreat, they retreated
ДНР лнр она начала отступать отступали
to Stary Sambir, they retreated a little, so
под Старый Самбор отступали немножко так
different ones retreated to Stanislavov Yes, and
под станиславова отступали разные Да и
then Russia intervened
тогда вмешалась Россия
Yes, it intervened in the fourteenth year when
Да вмешалась в четырнадцатом году когда
Yes, in the fourteenth year, in the devil Yes She led
Да в четырнадцатом в чертом Да Она вела
her troops Yes, so that Bandera would not reach
свои войска Да чтобы Бандера не дошёл до
Donetsk Lugansk Yeah
Донецка Луганска Угу
right And what do you know, this grandson
правильно А что вы знаете вот этот внук
of Bandera Yes, who captured
Бандеры Да который вот захватывал
Lugansk  what are his
Луганск какие его
ideas? Well, I don’t know, he’s a
идеи Ну я не знаю он
Nazi. Well, probably if he attacked
нацист Ну наверное если он напал на
the Donbass, the Nazi reported to Lugansk anyway.
Донбасс донес Луганск по-любому нацист
Yes, he knows. Maybe it’s good to have some kind of power,
Да его знает Может власть какую-то
but there’s one thing I don’t understand,
хорошо а вот я одно не понимаю вот
look, I’m a citizen of the Russian
смотрите Я гражданин Российской
Federation, I’m originally from St. Petersburg, I live in
Федерации Я из Питера родом живу в
British Well, I have two citizenships, also
Британии Ну у меня два гражданства ещё
British. You are also citizens of the Russian
Британское Вы тоже Граждане Российской
Federation. Why do we citizens of the Russian
Федерации Зачем нам гражданам Российской
Federation need Putin to fit into
Федерации чтоб Путин вписывался в
the showdown between Lugansk, Donetsk and
разборке Луганска Донецка и
Bandar? Well, because
бандар Ну потому что
there is a Russian population  the
там русское население тоже
Russian population also lived like this and lives in Germany
жил так русское население и в Германии
and that’s it, but if these are citizens of Ukraine,
живёт и всё но если это граждане Украины
all this is Ukraine, this is Bandera’s showdown with
всё это Украина это разборки Бандеры с
these miners like well, well, it’s just that
этими шахтёрами типа ну ну просто видать
initially this Donbass wanted to
изначально же вот этот вот Донбасс хотел
secede, but I don’t know if
отсоединиться но я не знаю хотел ли он
at that time he wanted to join  That’s
на тот момент присоединиться к России
why he stood up for Russia, as if to defend him. Why?
поэтому он как на защиту встал А зачем
Well, for example, now, uh, for example,
Ну например вот сейчас ээ там например
somewhere in other countries there are some
где-то в других странах какие-то тоже
unrest there too. We’re not running to bomb people there in
там волнения Мы же не бежим там людей
cities. Well, yes, but you can see how much
города Ну да но видать то что сколько
it is 8  years it
это 8 лет
was like this in the fourteenth year and in the
было так в четырнадцатом году да в
fourteenth year Putin, instead
четырнадцатом году Путин вместо того
of allowing Bandera to arrest all these
чтобы дал чтоб Бандера этих всех
rebels and bring peace to
повстанцев э арестовал и принёс мир в
Donetsk Lugansk Yes, Putin took uh
Донецк Луганск Да Путин взял ээ
occupied the Crimea Donetsk and
оккупировал Крым Донецк и
Lugansk in the fourteenth year, not allowing
Луганск в четырнадцатом году не дав
Bandera to enter Donetsk, he stopped
бандере зайти в Донецк он остановил
Bandera like  5 km before Donetsk and made the
бандеру типа за 5 км до Донецка и сделал
demarcation line signed with Bandero
линию разграничения подписал с бандеро
Minsk agreements heard about the
минские соглашения слышали про
Minsk agreements signed with Bandera
подписанные с бандеро минские соглашения
Yes, we don’t honestly know where Bandera and Putin signed the
Да вот а где Бандера с Путиным подписал
Minsk
минские
agreements Let’s do the
соглашения мы не знаем честно Давай так
Minsk agreements It’s clear in Minsk in
минские соглашения Понятно в Минске в
Minsk correct Yes In what year did Bandera
Минске правильно Да В каком году Бандера
sign the Minsk agreements with Putin Well
подписал с Путиным минские соглашения Ну
it turns out in the fourteenth in the
получается в четырнадцатом в
fourteenth correct  first Minsky in the
четырнадцатом правильно первый Минский в
fourteenth second in the fifth Yes
четырнадцатом вторый в пятом Да
Absolutely right you are like you
Абсолютно верно вы это вам типа вам
were told this at school or where did you
рассказывали это в школе или вы где
see me at school  I don’t remember I don’t remember
видели в школе я не помню не помню чтобы
telling you this How do you know all this
это рассказывать Откуда вы всё это
about Bandera, the Minsk
знаете там про бандеру минские
agreements, what did grandfather
соглашения дедушка что дедушка
tell you In what
рассказывал В каком
year Well, in general, I was
году Ну вот вообще Я раньше никогда там
never interested in politics there before. It’s clear what
политикой не интересовалась Понятно
happened to everyone, it affected us, well, you
поступило каждого нас коснулось ну ты
start watching and reading, and here in
начинаешь смотреть читать и вот в дцать
1920  That's about when February
ВМ году Вот примерно вот когда февраль
started right here, this one
вот этот вот началась прямо сама вот эта
got really scary Yes, from lack of understanding
вот сво страшно стало Да от непонимания
Why for what And
Почему за что И
grandfather told everything Well, some
всё дедушка рассказал Ну какие-то такие
moments like that Cool And this is what year he
моменты Прикольно А это в каком году он
PM 14th semester
ПМ 14м сем
was  and grandfather now understands where he lives in
было а дедушка сейчас где живёт в
Yakutia And that he is not going to defend the
Якутии понял А что он не идёт защищать
people of Donbass, he is 76 years old Well, nothing
народ Донбасса ему 76 лет Ну так ничего
is fertilized, so how does grandfather know
удобрення так что а откуда дедушка знает
these details about Bandera, the Minsk
Эти детали про Бандеры минские
agreements Well, he also most likely
соглашения Ну тоже скорее всего историю
studies history, but grandfather, by the way, did not
изучает изучал а дедушка кстати не
tell this interesting  the moment
рассказывал вот этот интересный момент
when Bandera wanted to return
как Бандера хотел вернуть Украине
nuclear weapons to Ukraine in 22
ядерное оружие в два втором
years No, well, when I started calling him, it
году Нет ну когда я ему начала звонить
was understandably scary that
понятное дело страшно было что вообще
what was happening at all.
что происходит А вдруг на Ну как бы и
and it started here Yes,
знал Ну сейчас уже и у нас началось Да
now the Kursk region Bandera’s people
сейчас уже курскую область бандеровцы
have captured, now Bandera’s people are shelling the
захватили сейчас бандеровцы обстреливают
Bryansk region there Nizhny Novgorod Tatarstan
брянскую там Нижний Новгород Татарстан
even flew at us in the Leningrad region
даже в нас в Ленинградскую область
Well, yes, drones
залетала Ну да беспилотники по весне
flew in in the spring All these Banderas, they won’t
прилетали Всё эти бандер они же они не
stop
остановятся
anymore Well, I hope that someday it’s still the same
уже Ну надеюсь что когда-то всё равно
will end there there is this one
это закончится там есть это такой один
this leader of Bandera's Ataman
этот предводитель бандеровцев Атаман
they have there this Dmitry Korchinsky
такой у них там этот Дмитрий корчинский
maybe
может
heard he he proclaimed yes such
слышала он он провозгласил да такой
Bandai's slogan that peace is not the absence of
лозунг бандай что мир это не отсутствие
war, peace is the absence of Moscow, that
войны мир - это отсутствие Москвы то
is, they want,
есть они хотят
yes, yes they want to destroy Moscow, yes they
да да они хотят уничтожить Москву да они
say that as long as Moscow exists,
говорят что пока существует Москва
Moscow is the world center of evil. The Kremlin, they
Москва - это мировой центр зла Кремль
say that the Kremlin is a
они говорят что вот Кремль - это
satanic temple, there is this star  the
сатанинское капище там вот эта звезда
satanic pentagram over the Kremlin has not yet
сатанинская над кремлём до сих пор не
been removed, yes, during the Soviet Union, Lenin
снята да При Советском Союзе Ленин же
hung it, yes, this is the satanic
повесил её Да это сатанинская
pentagram called yes, the pentagonal
пентаграмма называется да пятиугольная
Star and Lenin  Lenin's corpse was placed in the
Звезда и Ленина труп Ленина положили в
Mausoleum But this is some kind of devilry
Мавзолей Но это какая-то бесовщина
According to
Согласно
Well, by the way, you know what I heard that until
Ну кстати знаете что я слышала что пока
Lenin is buried in Russia there will not be a hundred
Ленин не Похоронен в России не будет сто
That's because Look, this is an ancient
вот Вот потому что Смотри это же древний
necromantic rite Yes, when they take
обряд некромантской Да когда берут
a person, they don’t bury him in the ground Yes, they don’t
человека не закапывают в землю Да не
bury him  in short, then they mummify him
погребают чтобы он короче потом они его
and bring the children to worship him, everyone
и детей приводят поклоняться му там все
comes there, you were in this
приходят ты была в этом
Mausoleum, but he doesn’t come there to worship
Мавзолее но туда не приходит поклоняться
there you can’t even
там там нельзя вообще даже шаг
stop a step stop you were there no I
останавливать стоп вы были там нет я не
wasn’t I wanted to get there but it didn’t work out
была я хотела попасть но не получилось
so look I was there how
так вот смотри я был там как
organized it was so you could see the
организовано для того чтобы ты увидел
laziness you’re coming for Uvi to
лень ты подходишь для того чтобы Уви
bend over like that and look
нужно вот так нагнуться и посмотреть да
and it works  Everyone who comes up, he
и получается Каждый кто подходит он
bows to Lenin's corpse, I understand how they
кланяется Ленину трупу поняла как они
made the magic Well, look there
сделали магические Ну да смотрите там
anyway, it's the same way it stands, it turns out
всё равно там он же как стоит получается
the building looks like this, it stands in the middle, there are two
здание вот такое он стоит в середине два
exits and you're walking, I know that you
выхода и ты идёшь я знаю то что там шаг
can't stop the step there right, right
нельзя останавливать правильно правильно
Yes, and  you walk and in order to
Да и ты идёшь и вот для того чтобы
see everyone starts bowing their heads
увидеть все начинают наклонять головы
because they deliberately walk a little
потому что они специально проходят чуть
higher and everyone tilts it turns out everyone
выше да и все наклоняют получается все
bows to the corpse of Lenin, this is a magical
кланяются трупу Ленина это магический
ancient Sumerian ritual, yes,
древний да шумерский обряд такой да вот
I think so too, yes, my mother goes to
я тоже считаю да вот у меня мама ходит в
this one in Nevsky  the cathedral, yes, it says that
этот в Невский собор да то говорит что
Lenin is not buried yet. Yes, it will be,
пока Ленин типа не погребён Да это будет
well, Russia. A damned country and such horror. Well,
ну Россия Проклятая страна и такой ужас
yes, yes, I also heard this, that
Ну да да да Я тоже вот это слышала что
until he is buried. And you have some  I
пока его не похоронят А у вас какие-то
have acquaintances who are in the war. I have a
знакомые есть которые на войне У меня
brother. He did his military service. Well, for a year
брат Он срочную службу проходил Ну год и
he was sent on a business trip there and where he is
его в командировку кинули туда и где он
now, he is now already
сейчас он сейчас уже
at home. My classmate Sanya Prokhorov
дома У меня одноклассник Саня Прохоров
was sitting at the same desk; the medalist was a
был сидели за одной партой медалист был
Gold medalist; graduated from school; went to
Золотой медаль окончил школу пошёл
work at the university in St. Petersburg  and in the
работать в университет в Питере а в
twenty-second year they mobile him Zro and
двадцать втором году его мобили Зро и
sent him, like, they said first for
отправили типа сказали сначала на
training in the Bryansk region Yes, and then
обучение в брянскую область Да а потом
they threw him into the assault on Bakhmut
бросили его На штурм бахмута
and, in short, he spoke to his mother Well, she
и короче с мамкой его говорил Ну она
cried, of course,
плакала конечно
uh, I say A  what even happened yes There’s
ээ говорю А что хоть случилось да Там
a bullet there’s a shell In short, she
пуля там снаряд Короче она мне
showed me photographs of him, his colleagues
фотографии показывала его сослуживцы
like skid uh, in short, he ran. He ran
типа скида ээ короче он бежал Он бежал
towards these Ukrainian cops shouting Hurray. I
на копы эти украинские с криками Ура Я
don’t know what they did with them, yes. But
не знаю что там с ними делали да Но
in short, they stupidly released 100 of
короче они вот так тупо их выпустили 100
them and  they ran, they had to
человек и они побежали им нужно было
run to the trenches and capture the trench, and they were
добежать до окопов и захватить окоп и им
flying at this bunch of Drones, a bunch of
летели вот эта куча Дронов го куча
Drones, the Americans are giving the Ukrainians drones and  they're
Дронов американцы дают украинцам дроны и
flying right into his face, right in the face.
летят Ему прямо вот в лицо прямо в лицо
This is a drone that hit him with an explosion on
Это Дрон с взрывом попал ещё на
Ukrainian public pages. My mother sent me this,
украинских пабликах ходила мне это мама
in short, there's a video there, there's
скидывала там короче видео есть такой
this Robert Madyar in Ukraine, there's the main
этот Роберт мадяр в Украине там главный
megadrome, this Yes, he's these Well, the father of all
мегадром этот Да он эти Ну отец всех
these Drones, in short, a Bandera guy is like
этих Дрон ков короче бандеровец такой
that  tin and he posted a video
что жесть и он выкладывал у себя видео
with this one with Anya Prokhorov, my
вот с этим с Аней прохоровым моим
classmate, yes And he called the
одноклассником да И назвал
video headless hrobak hrobak - this is
видео безголовый хробак хробак - это
in Ukrainian  a worm like a headless
по-украински червяк типа безголовый
worm that in short a drone flies in on him, well,
червяк что ему короче залетает Дрон ну
Sanya Prokhorov runs he with a machine gun runs
Саня Прохоров бежит он с автоматом бежит
runs to him Drone not only do they
бежит ему Дрон они мало того что они
hit ours with drones, they also film
дронами бьют по наше они ещё снимают
separately from above the Drone how it all
сверху отдельно Дрон как это всё
happens then the cartoons show
происходит потом мультики показывают
their Banderites like and their
своим бандеровцам типа и своим
Americans Yes and  Sanya Prokhora flies
американцам Да и Сани Прохора прилетает
in the face Drone head, that's just a head and
в лицо Дрон башка вот просто башка а
Sanya runs another 2 meters, it turns out, well,
Саня ещё 2 м пробегает получается ну
the body  runs by inertia Yes, he falls
тело бежит по инерции Да вот и он падает
and in short, he shakes Yes, his head
и короче трясётся Да голова там
rolled there and Sanya Prokhorov, like,
покатилась а Саня Прохоров типа без
ran without a head, two of these and his mother, his mother
головы пробежал два это и мамка мамка
cried so much, in short, he says, damn he was an excellent student
так плакала короче говорит блин отличник
and he knew mathematics well Yes,
был да математику хорошо знал Да вот
Russian is the only language he
русский язык единственный он нашего
passed in our class with an A, we  all four, there
класса сдал на пятёрку мы все четыре там
were three types, oh, did any of your
три типа было ой такое А у вас кто-то из
friends die? Well, look in St.
знакомых есть погибших Ну смотрите в
Petersburg, it’s like here, I don’t know, there’s no
Питере как бы тут я не знаю тут нет
such excitement about  I’m dead, I’m from a
такого ажиотажа по погибшим я вот из
small town, it’s clear that
маленького Городка понятное дело то что
everyone there, well, every
там вообще там каждый там ну каждую
week this cargo of 200 arrives Well, in St.
неделю этот груз 200 приезжает Ну в
Petersburg, no one cares Yes, there, like no one
Питере всем пофиг Да там типа уме никто
knew, Yes, it’s true And there, it’s like we’re like a
и не знал Да правда А там как бы мы как
big family Here in this guti, everyone  a
семья большая Вот в этой гути каждую
week someone died Cruz 200 Yes, a
неделю был кто-то погибший Круз 200 Да
steady stream of young guys are coming,
приезжает стабильно молодые парни кто-то
someone is dying from Drones and
Ну кто-то вот от Дронов умирает а
how much is the population in your city
сколько у вас население в городе
26,000 26,000 every week  someone
26.000 26.000 каждую неделю кто-то
died and
погибший да
zhezha yes and Well, different stories, let’s say
жежа да и Ну разные истории вот допустим
recently a guy This was the beginning of November, it
недавно парень Вот это начало ноября
turns out he was a year in Ukraine,
было он он получается был год на Украине
19 years old, the kid was a year old, well,
19 лет пацану он был год на ну на сво
then he came home from an injury for
потом приехал домой по ранению на
six months, everything seems to have recovered, he’s
полгода всё вроде восстановился его
back to normal  Yakutsk and he is
обратно на Якутск и он
there, but apparently the psyche could not stand it
там но видать психика не выдержала всё
anyway, there are young brains there, nothing. Well,
равно там кого молодые мозги ничего Ну а
wait, it’s 19 years since he got on
подожди как 19 лет как он попал на
his own, he went for the
сво сам пошёл за
money, that is, he was taken on an urgent basis and
деньгами то есть его взяли на срочку и
there he was  give me a contract
там его на контракт склони
Yes, I just don’t understand, too, that’s how they’re
Да я просто не понимаю тоже вот как как
sitting at the military registration and enlistment offices, they see a young
вот военкоматах сидят видят молодой
guy, tell him Go home You still have to live
парень скажи ему Иди домой Тебе ещё жить
and live like this, wait and see The point is that
и жить так подожди смотри Дея в том что
they were given an order Yes, they need so much
им спустили приказ Да нужно столько они
But no one wants to go anymore, like  and
А никто же не хочет уже идти да типа и
they are already young, I also watched
они уже вот молодых я тоже смотрел
so many nineteen-year-olds,
столько девятнадцатилетний вот у моего
my classmate had Alyonka
моей одноклассницы была Алёнка
Nikiforova, in short, a pretty girl.
Никифорова короче симпатичная девчонка
Well, I had a lot of fights with her in the
Ну там у меня с ней шуры-муры были в
ninth grade  Yes, you know,
девятом классе Да ну понимаете
we met. Then she went to
по Встречались мы Потом она уехала в
another city to study. I went to London and I
другой город учиться Я Лондон поехал и я
will say that she has a son, he
скажу такое что у неё сын как раз ему
was 18 years old in the twenty-second year, in the
вот было 18 лет в двадцать втором году в
second year he was 18 years old. He went to urgent care,
д втором году 18 лет Пошёл на срочку
they did something to him there.  They threatened that
что-то там ему сделали пригрозили что
let’s put it in short,
давай короче
it’s like either you’ll go or be happy, it’s
это типа или поедешь или счасть вот
Dagestan It’s tough there Yes, it’s right there
Дагестан Там жёстко Да там прямо
Oh he didn’t say No, his Dagestanis are
О он не он сказал Нет его дагестанцы
just shorter than his nose, my mother
просто короче ему нос мама короче
gave it to me in short,
скидывала Мне
Alyonka told me  maybe you
Алёнка она говорила может ты как-то
can somehow help there from this there for a
можешь помочь там из этого там на
lawyer like or that we sent
адвоката типа или что мы там прислали
money for a lawyer Well, in short, while the
деньги на адвоката Ну короче пока
lawyer was sorting it out, he signed it and
адвокат это разбирал он так и подписал
finished it off, he signed these documents on
его добили он подписал эти документы на
his Yes, the contract on his and in short, while the
сво Да контракт на сво и короче пока
lawyer is in  it was a burden In short, 2
адвокат это в тягомотина была Короче 2
months or already sun No, by the way, there is
месяца ило уже вс Нет там кстати есть
some kind of gap, I don’t remember
какой-то тоже промежуток я не помню
the truth, what is it that you can break this contract
правда какой что ты можешь этот контракт
No no, it’s BC, it’s a fake from the
разорвать Нет нет это ВС это фейк с
moment of signing nothing while the military
момента подписание никакого пока военная
is going on War  with no breaks in the contract
идёт Война с никаких разрывов контракта
under any circumstances, only death
ни в каких условиях только смерть
breaks the contract, that’s the same story,
разрывает контракт вот тоже история была
my brother served with him, there were colleagues with him,
вот у меня брат служил с ним сослуживцы
and before demobilization, well, two weeks or
были и вот до дембеля Ну недели две либо
one week remained and they,
одна неделя оставалась и они
in short,
короче вми
saw that there were three of them Well, that’s all he
это увидел их трое человек было Ну и всё
said  Well, either a contract or nothing at all, and
сказал ну либо контракт либо вообще
there was moral pressure. And
никак также там морально надавил А у
one guy, in short, has a mother, she’s some kind of
одного пацана короче мама она какой-то
cool lawyer. Well, in short, she
юрист вообще крутой Ну она короче его
fought him off, she was able to fight him off. Well, maybe she
отбила смогла отбить Ну может она как-то
threatened somehow, but I don’t know something about it. Yes,
там пригрозила да там что-то не зна Да
she says  I don’t care, send him to the lip,
она говорит пофигу отправляйте на губу
beat him, let him be there, these Well, the bars or
бейте его пусть он там эти Ну штанги или
whatever they are carrying punishment, but he
что они там наказание таскают но
didn’t sign the contract. But these two
контракт Он не подписал А эти двое
signed and went, well, just
подписали и поехали ну просто
Well, what is it, I really don’t
Ну что там да я правда не
know, yes, well, yes, these are stories, of course there
знаю да Ну вот да это истории Конечно
are, Yes, we have  it turns out Well, from the class
есть Да у нас получается Ну вот С класса
Three guys who were Yes Sanya
Трое парней которые были Да Саня
Prokhorov two more they are already that and two
Прохоров ещё двое они уже того и у двух
girls’ children have already died in the war and you
девчонок дети уже погибли на войне а вы
lived here in which you lived here in St. Petersburg in
тут в каком жили что вы тут в Питере в
which district you lived not in Vyborg I
каком районе жили не пом в Выборге я жил
I lived in Vyborg Yes, I say father, look,
я в Выборге Жил да я говорю отец смотри
father came to study in St. Petersburg, yes to
отец приехал учиться в Питер да
students, where did he live there in a dorm or
студентам где он там жил в общаге или
not? Well, in short, when he and his mother
нет Ну короче когда они с мамой они
settled in the sample After that, I
поселились в выборке После этого я 8
was born in Perm 8,
родился жили
so I’m in
поэтому я в
what you 43 right  43 years old, yes 43 years old, you’re
что вам 43 верно 43 года да 43 года вы
just my dad, too, in the first year of the
просто у меня папа тоже во первого т
first year. Yes, I
первого года Да я ещё При Советском
was born in the Soviet Union. But then
Союзе родился Но тогда тогда ещ
St. Petersburg wasn’t called
санктпетербург не назывался
St. Petersburg yet.  was called n and for
санктпетербургом он назывался н и
some reason the region remained Leningradskaya
область почему-то осталась Ленинградская
and St. Petersburg was renamed like yes, yes, yes,
а Питер переименовали типа да ну дада да
yes, but Myt Well, before that, we also just
Ну мы просто до этого тоже нам дяденька
came across a guy and so he started telling us you We were
попался и вот он начал нам говорить вы
attacked Uh-huh And they, too, I, I,
На нас напали Угу А они тоже я я же
Look at me there  there is a flag of Ukraine, I
Смотри у меня там стоит флаг Украины я
put up the flag of Ukraine and talked to them about how
ставил флаг Украины и общался с ними как
you feel about Russians in the
вы относитесь вот к русским в
UK and they’re like, well, here you are in
Великобритании да и они типа ну вот ты в
Britain, you’re still Russian, it’s your fault,
Британии ты всё равно русский ты виноват
in short, heap something on me  I’m melting Well, it’s
короче что-то там мне наваливай Я таю Ну
the other way around for us Why didn’t you leave
ябо а нам наоборот А почему вы не уехали
And why are you sitting there So you like
А что вы там сидите Значит вам нравится
Ponya And I say, damn, I’ve been living in Britain for 18 years already,
Поня А я говорю блин я 18 лет уже в
I’m generally like the hammer of
Британии живу я вообще типа молоту
Russia like they’re still Russian
России типа они всё равно ты русский У
You have a Russian passport I say  yes,
тебя есть русский паспорт я говорю да
like yes, they’re like, you’re to blame, you
типа да они вот типа ты виноват ты
support, you pay taxes. Yes, well, I
поддерживаешь вы налоги платите Да ну я
say, like, no, look, I say. So,
говорю типа Не ну я смотри я говорю Так
I’m like, I support tsu because I’m
что я типа я поддерживаю цу потому что я
from London, here I always transfer part of my salary
из Лондона тут часть своей зарплаты
to  The Armed Forces of
всегда Перевожу на Вооружённые силы
Ukraine because I think yes, that we are,
Украины потому что я считаю да что мы
well, we are wrong, we attacked there
как бы ну мы не правы мы напали там
Bandera is not Bandera Yes, we are their
Бандера не Бандера Да мы это ихний
Bandera,
бандеровский
Bandera showdowns Yes, this is their
бандеровские разборки Да это ихняя
country and we are now it turns out I also
страна и мы сейчас получается Я вот тоже
can’t understand if we attacked to
не могу понять если мы напали чтобы
protect from Bandera  Yes, why did we
защитить от бандеровцев Да почему мы
bomb the Donetsk cities of
разбомбили именно Донецкие города
Mariupol bakhmut, all where Donetsk and
Мариуполь бахмут все где жили Донецкие и
Lugansk people lived,
Луганские люди
so that we could later rebuild and launder
чтобы потом отстраивать и отмывать
money? Well, but you can’t return the people to Me
деньги Ну да а людей же не вернёшь Мне
it seems that this is all war - this is a lot of
кажется что это всё война - это огромные
money, there’s just a turnover of money there
деньги вот там просто оборот денег идёт
No, I just don’t like the fact that they blame
Нет мне просто не нравится то что винят
us. Personally, I
нас Вот лично меня я вот никого на войну
didn’t send anyone to war And I didn’t sign any laws. By
не отправляла И никакие там законы не
the way, what do you think whose
подписывала А ты кстати как считаешь чей
Crimea is?  Ukraine is also asked
Крым вот меня все Украин спрашивают тоже
this question. Well, he has been Russian for 8 years.
это вопрос Ну он уже 8 лет русский
That is, you think that he is Russian,
То есть ты считаешь что это русский
which means you will support him. So I think that
значит ты поддержишь е Вот я считаю что
we should give Crimea to Ukraine. Because
Крым мы должны отдать Украине Потому что
this is Ukrainian territory. We recognized it
это украинская территория Мы её были
and we attacked.  they took Crimea, if
признали и мы напали забрали Крым если
you say that Crimea is Russian, then it
ты говоришь что Крым - это русский то ты
turns out that you support this war, I don’t
получается поддерживаешь эту войну я не
support the war. I say that we should
поддерживаю войну Я говорю что мы должны
give Crimea to Ukraine. I just no, I mean, according to the
отдать Украине Крым Я просто нет я он ну
maps, it’s considered ours. I mean, according to the
по картам он считается наш В смысле по
maps, ours, look at the fourteenth year, yes
картам наш смотри четырнадцатый год да
Our troops  We entered Crimea Donetsk Lugansk
Наши войска зашли в Крым Донецк Луганск
to drive Bandera’s followers out of there Yes, but
чтобы выбить оттуда бандеровцев Да но
this is territory
это территория
we
мы не
shouldn’t Well, according to the documents, it is now Our
должны Ну по документам же он сейчас Наш
Crimea, according to what documents did we all
Крым по каким документам это мы все
write this?  in the Constitution that we captured
писали в Конституцию что мы захватили
Crimea and we consider it ours, the whole world
Крым и мы считаем его нашим весь мир это
doesn’t consider it, the whole world says that Crimea
не считает весь мир говорит что Крым -
is Ukraine, so I live in London Yes,
это Украина вот я в Лондоне живу Да у
on our maps everywhere, in short, Crimea is
нас всюду на картах короче Крым - это
Ukraine, for us it is Russia, well, so is Kherson for you
Украина у нас это Россия ну так у вас и
- this is Russia, right, for me, from the fact
Херсон - это Россия пра вот мне от того
that the DPR LPR joined there, the fact that
что там присоединился дн ДНР лнр то что
Crimea was annexed to us, it
там Крым к нам присоединили
became worse for me, my mother. It’s not that it’s
хуже стало у меня у меня мамка Да не то
worse, it’s just that even let’s say
что хуже просто вот даже допустим
these people come  refugees
приезжают вот эти вот беженцы
Yes, they occupy preferential places there, that’s
Да они занимают там льготные места вот
all, yes, well, look, my
это вот всё да так Ну вот смотри у меня
mother is in Vyborg, yes, she says before her pension
мама в Выборге да говорит до сво пенсия
was like this, the prices were like this now, just
была такая цены были такие сейчас просто
for her pension, you get a pension of
на её пенсию вы она получает пенсию
21,000 rubles, that’s 200 dollars, I’m
21.000 руб это 200 долларов я ей
sending her help like  from onna because
присылаю помощь типа из онна потому что
well, it’s unrealistic to squeeze out yes She says
ну это нереально выжать да Она говорит
these people came in large numbers with them in Vyborg, she
эти понаехали у них короче в Выборге она
works as a nurse, she says
медсестрой работает говорит приехала
someone came from Donetsk, she was given a job
какая-то из Донецка её устроили потому
because  we need to arrange a decree somewhere there that
что нужно устраивать там где-то указ вти
all refugees must be loved in short and they
всех беженцев надо короче любить и её не
can’t fire her. She says she doesn’t
могут уволить Она говорит она ничего не
do anything, we speak for her, everything there, on
делает мы говорит за неё все там и
duty and really, but they can’t
дежурства и толком Да а её не могут
fire her because she’s on a quota
уволить потому что она по квоте потому
because she’s from Donetsk.  quota Yes, and I heard,
что она Донецкая по квоте Да и я слышал
like, that they even take them to universities. Yes,
типа что даже в университеты берут Да
these are the types of children there, then refugees
вот эти типа там дети сво потом беженцы
from Donbass, in short, they give them, like, places, but
с Донбасса короче им дают типа места а
our normal Russians cannot
нормальные наши русские не могут
get out of this, yes, no  so that even
поступить из этого да да не то чтоб даже
we have classmates who, here
у нас есть Одногруппники которые вот у
we have a girl, well, it turns out that
нас девчонка на ну вот получается
Eva is a refugee, she has a preferential place on Well, a
беженец Ева у неё льготное место по Ну
budgetary one. And there is a boy who, in general, is
бюджетное А есть мальчик который вообще
just an excellent student studying there. On a
просто там чуть ли не отличник учится На
headscarf. That’s
платке Вот от
why there is no justice in this,
этого Справедливости в этом нет да
because they  Damn, and I’ll say more Yes,
потому что они блин и я больше скажу Да
I met them here in Char Roulette, they
я вот встречал тут в Ча рулетке эти они
came there from Donetsk and there in St.
там с Донецка по приезжали да там в
Petersburg and so on, they’re crazy, stupid,
Питере и так дальше они офигевшие тупо
they think that  we Russians owe them,
они считают что мы россияне им должны
they say, yes, what should
они типа говорят Да что мы должны короче
we pay them, like there is this help? In short,
им платить типа там эти помощь Короче
like refugees of the mountains, go work, why?
как беженцы гор да иди работай почему
In short, my mother should [ __ ] work in Vyborg
Короче моя мама должна в Выборге блин
in three shifts in order for
пахать короче в три смены для того чтобы
herself to somehow survive besides her pension. Yes,  You're
себе кроме пенсии как-то выжить Да а ты
like, you came from Donetsk, damn it, a young
типа приехал из Донецка блин молодой
guy, in short, and damn you're sitting. Why don't they
парень короче и блин сидишь А что они не
go to defend their Donetsk, they want to?
идут защищать свой Донецк они хотят
Why Sanya Prokhorov, yes, our damn thing from
Почему Саня Прохоров да наш блин из
Vyborg should have died, like,
Выборга должен был короче умереть типа
under the bakhmut And you came here  in short, and
под бахмутом А ты тут приехал короче и
you live damn it in St. Petersburg, they’re totally freaked out, yes.
живёшь блин в Питере вообще офигевшие да
You, too, probably have some
У вас тоже наверное такие есть какие-то
who came from Donetsk, I’m freaked out and
которые из Донецка приехали офигеваю и
say, Let’s go defend our
говорят Давайте идите защищать наш
Donetsk Yeah, we’ll also soon become
Донецк Угу Мы тоже скоро станем
liable for military service. And you’re doctors of
военнообязанными А вы же медики
information. Yes, and you have some
информаци Да а у вас есть какие-то
friends  there are elders there Well, some
знакомые там старшие Ну какие-то
pharmacists who were taken to
фармацевты которых забрали на
the war by the way no no I think that when
войну кстати нет нет я думаю что когда
the floor is reached If suddenly God forbid Of course there
будет пол Если вдруг не дай Бог Конечно
will be a full-scale mobilization
будет полномасштабная та мобилизация
Well, everyone will go, we will all go,
прям Ну все пойдут все мы все пойдём да
yes, that’s all, and Where will you go? The thing is,
да всё а Куда пойдёте Дело в том что
look, here in London, they
смотри вот у нас в Лондоне типа
showed this Peter Jackson to an analyst.
показывали аналитику этот Питер джаксон
Well, the chief military analyst in Britain,
Ну военный аналитик главный в Британии
he showed that Russia cannot
он показывал что Россия не может
call all these people to war
призвать на войну всех этих людей потому
because  he has no weapons, no cars Well,
что у него нету оружия нету машин Ну
like, where is it not like you
типа куда это же не то что ты с дубина
’re going to run from a club, no, no, what to fight with.
будешь бежать нету нету чем воевать
I don’t know where. Well, just according to the logic, the
Всё я не знаю куда Ну просто по логике
pharmacists will be the first to be thrown because Who
фармацевтов первых кинут потому что Кто
will prepare the medicine  Well, although now is the
будет готовить лекарство Ну хотя сейчас
Age of high technology that these medicines are
Век технологий высоких что этих лекарств
just like that yes Question yes Question
просто вот так вот да Вопрос да Вопрос
What to cook from now because of the sanctions, well,
Из чего готовить сейчас из-за санкций ну
I told you too, my mother, my mother, my
вас же я тоже мама говорила мама у меня
nurse says there’s a real problem, uh,
медсестра говорит реально проблема ээ
the hospital can’t even buy these from them
них больница не может закупить вот эти
what is
даже как
it like saline solution? I know this, but you know
оно физраствор Вот это я знаю но знаете
what I’ll tell you in response to this: people themselves
что я вам на это скажу что люди сами
sometimes create a shortage when it
бывают порой создают дефицит когда
started. This war Oh, not a
началась Вот эта война Ой не
war, a
война
special operation No, not a special operation, but
спецоперация Нет не спецоперация а ковид
covid covid yeah, floor this one here is one
ковид ага пол вот этот вот кто-то один
grandson that won’t  there will be toilet paper
вну что будет не будет туалетной бумаги
KNU paper Yes, they created
КНУ бумагу Да создали
a shortage, it’s cool and just like that with
дефицит прикольно и точно так
medications. I don’t know, but I know that the
лекарствами Я не знаю вот я знаю что
pressure in the region is now really a problem
давле на области сейчас реально проблема
with some kind of saline solution, but in the same
какая-то с физраствором но в той же
Siberia in Yakutia everything is fine. That is, there is
Сибири в якути всё нормально То есть тут
some kind of excitement here, you can see about this  the
какой-то ажиотаж видать на этот
saline solution went, everyone started
физраствор пошёл все начали сломя голову
buying it at breakneck speed. So I’m just not into it either.
его покупать Вот и просто я тоже не по
Well, saline solution is just damn sodium
Ну физраствор это ж просто блин натрий
chlorine with water, you know,
хлор с водичкой понимаешь
distilled,
дистиллированной
so actually Yes, but  what’s the problem it’s
так фактически Да но в чём проблема это
stupid salt with Wow, it’s purified there yes In the World Cup It’s
тупо соль с Во ну там очищен да В ЧМ Это
not some kind of chemical
же не какое-то там химическое
organic compound I don’t understand how
органическое соединение Я не понимаю как
we Russia is a great technological power
мы Россия велико технологическая держава
cannot provide many millions in the city there
не может обеспечить в городе там много
yes sodium chloride solution Well
миллионом да раствор хлорида натрия Ну
now it’ll do it  Yes, I don’t know the
сейчас ещё его наделает Да будет не знаю
truth, somehow in the spring there was no
правда как-то вот по весне не было
Ringer
Рингера
anywhere and with antibiotics as now it’s
нигде а с антибиотиками как сейчас
also a problem That there is a shortage of some
тоже нома Что дефицит там каких-то
pills in general everything is
таблеток вообще всё всё
fine clothes Well, by the way, that’s in the
нормально одежда Ну вот кстати вот в
plan when everyone started leaving
плане вот когда начали уходить все
brands, of course, spoil the quality of the clothes a little,
бренды конечно немножко качество одежды
but the Russians, the Russians, don’t sew
подпортить вот русские русские не шьют
well, yes Well, yes And the food, smartphones,
качественно да Ну да А еда смартфоны
iPhones, everything is there, in principle,
Айфоны всё есть вообще в принципе
you go into the store, all the shelves are full,
заходишь в магазин все полки забитые всё
whatever you want, take it, we’ve already even so
что хочешь бери мы уже даже настолько
you come in and even look at the sweets
ты заходишь и даже вот на сладкое
and think that’s not it  I don’t want
смотришь и думаешь не это я не хочу
something, something doesn’t taste good anymore, as
что-то что-то уже как-то и не вкусно как
if How much is your
будто бы А сколько у вас
scholarship? We study on a paid basis. I
стипендия мы на платной основе учимся
understand. How much is a scarf now?  150,000 per
понял А сколько сейчас платка 150.000 в
year in dollars 163,163 Yes, dollars and
год по долларов 163 163 Да долларов и
this is not a higher education, this is a secondary
это не высшее образование это сред
college 300,000 a year at
колледж 300.000 год в университете
Kapets University, well, yes, and this is not the same
Капец ну да и это е не самый такой
university with St. Petersburg State University, we have 500,000
университет с СПбГУ у нас 500.000
560 understood Well, yes, this is like Damn it’s hard, but
560 понял Ну да это типа Блин жесть а
it turns out that your parents are helping you
получается вам типа родители помогают
so that you can study on a headscarf. Yes, well.
чтобы вы На платке учились Да ну
At first, I somehow tried to get
Поначалу я сама как-то пыталась набрала
credits myself and I sat down, now
кредитов и я села сейчас
they’re helping me  got loans for education Well,
помогают набрали кредитов на обучение Ну
yes, there is an educational loan at 3%
да есть же образовательный кредит по 3%
3% yes, well, that’s [ __ ]. They just told me
3% да да ну там фигня Просто мне сказали
that I can
что я могу каждый этот каждый семестр
take it out every semester and somehow the girl who
брать и мне как-то девушка которая там
arranged it for me there for the first time did something wrong
мне это оформляла впервые она что-то не
As they later explained to me, they had to
то сделала как мне потом объяснили мне
make a tranche for the entire amount
должны были сделать транш на всю сумму
for 2 years of study. But they did it for me only
на 2 года обучения А мне сделали только
for one semester and, accordingly, until I
на один семестр и соответственно пока я
pay this off, I can’t take the second T.
этот не выплачу я второй Т не могу взять
Pony
Поня
Thanks. Cool, yes. How much do
Спасибо Прикольно да А сколько
you have left to
получается тебе осталось
repay the loan? Yes
выплатить кредит Да
well, you are
ну ты
60 I am myself I have a salary of
60 я я сама У меня зарплата
20,000 I sometimes get help from my parents and the
20.000 мне иногда помогают родители а
salary Who do you work what is the salary I
зарплата кем вы работаете что зарплата Я
work in a pharmacy but I don’t work as an order I
работаю в аптеке но я работаю не заказ Я
work 20 hours a week I receive
работаю по 20 часов в неделю принимаю
goods 20 hours a week - That’s half the
товар 20 часо в неделю - Это половина
working week Well  yes yes, that
рабочей недели получается Ну да да то
is, if you worked full time you would
есть если бы вы работали полный вы
receive 40,000 rubles Well, yes, 390 dollars,
получали 40.000 руб Ну да 390 долларов
well for St. Petersburg this is generally a small salary
ну для Питера это вообще мелкая зарплата
Well, because I only work with
Ну так потому что я работаю всего лишь с
goods no  Pervostolnik
товаром нет первостольник хорошо
gets good money from Vo What is Pervol which
получают от Во что такое перволь который
costs Zaka Well Pharma far receives 700 dollars
зака стоит Ну Фарма фар 700 долларов
a month Well for St. Petersburg it’s
получает в месяц Ну для Питера это мало
not even 1,000
Даже даже не не 1.000
dollars No If you want, you can
долларов Нет Если захотеть то можно и
get 100 120 12 we have a lot 1,200
100 получать 120 12 у нас многи 1.200 -
is the ceiling yes yes Well  this is normal in
это потолок да да Ну это нормально в
principle for students No, well, I’m talking to a
принципе студентам Не ну я же говорю
pharmacist. That is, it turns out that in your
фармацевт То есть получается в вашей
field the ceiling is 1,200 yes
сфере потолок - это 1.200 да
yes  And then you still have to live up to this
да И то это ещё надо дожить до этого
in the pharmacy. Yes, in the pharmacy. In
именно в аптеке Да именно в аптеке В
principle, if
принципе если
there are no managers, they can get more from
нет завед могут ту больше получать у
me. The manager, the manager who is
меня заведующая заведующая которая
the main one. Yes, in the pharmacy she goes to Cuba
главная самая Да в аптеке она и на Кубу
and Thailand, I think she earns 1,200 from the
и в Таиланд я думаю она 1.200 гребёт с
pharmacy. That’s cool.  Well, she's probably still
аптеки Прикольно вот ну она наверное ещё
She's probably still sleeping with the director of the pharmacy The
Она наверное ещё с директором аптеки
director of the pharmacy is
спит директор аптеки он находится
in a hiatus
в зависло
Oh, I can hear me I heard the
о развила слышно меня Я у слышал
director of the pharmacy is here He's here
директор аптеки находится он находится
Lord, this is a chain of pharmacies, this is a chain of pharmacies,
Господи это сеть аптек это сеть аптек
this is  not Pumice Well, everything is correct with her
это не Пемза Ну всё правильно у неё У
He has a lot of
него много
managers again, the
заведующих снова
development is stuck there Oh he is in Perm
зависла разви там О он находится в Перми
in Perm Yes in Perm Yes, well, it turns out that is, that
в Перми Да в Перми Да ну получается то
is, to him in Perm, like, or he comes
есть к нему в Перм типа или он приезжает
to one manager to another, in short, well,
к одной заведующей к другой короче ну
like, because just like that  do you know
типа потому что просто так знаете
how many of these pharmacies there are in Russia? It’s actually a
сколько этих аптек по России это вообще
big network, yes. Well, you
ну прямо сеть большая да Ну вот он
see, he’s like a sultan, well, yes, well, I don’t
видишь он как султан такой ну да ну я не
believe that they pay her 200,000 just for the
верю что ей платят 200.000 просто за
director’s role. Well, for the manager. Well.  for
директорское Ну за заведующую Ну за
sales for good Yes, she’s from plans,
продажи за хорошие Да она же от планов
pharmacists are fulfilling plans, the bonus is
фармацевты выполняют планы ей премия
coming to her, something is correct,
прилетает что-то там правильно
merchandising has been designed for her, the bonus is
мерчандайзинг оформили ей премия
coming to her, the video was recorded, the bonus is
прилетает видео записали премия
coming, and all that understood, that is,
прилетает и всё такое понял то есть
work TV, the bonus is coming to her, yes, yes,
работай ТВ прилетает премия ей да да да
because who is the director of the spokes,
потому что кто спиц директором
she is Well
она Ну
yes But if you were offered Dash, you
да А вот если бы вам предложили Даш
will be the head of the manager.
будете заведующей заведующей Ну там
Well, for example, there will be some kind of aromatic
например ну какие-то ароматические
relationship with the director. No But
отношения с директором нужно будет Нет А
for  300,000 a month No, no plans to
за 300.000 месяц Нет вообще в планах
open my own pharmacy No no And for a million
свою аптеку открыть Не не А за миллион
a month no honor doesn’t cost anything like that What does honor have to do with
месяц нет честь не стоит ничего так При
it Nuno It could be for love
чём тут честь нуно Это по любви могла
the spa of a person I don’t love
спа человека которого я не люблю
moral so it’s not necessary to
моральный так не обязательно
sleep different ways of
спать разные способы
satisfaction
удовлетворения
no If for love then yes  And so no Well,
нет Если по любви то да А так нет Ну
like, yes, well, every manager She loves the
типа да ну каждая заведующая Она любит
director Oh this is definitely her too Well,
директора О это однозначно она ж тоже Ну
for 200,000 she develops such love
она за 200.000 такая любов у неё
not just I know that
развивается не не просто я знаю что вот
this is in
это в
cinema in art and in
кинематографе в искусстве и в
pharmaceuticals there only through
фармацевтике там только через постель
bed bed Yes, I don’t know, my grandmother has her own
постель Да не знаю у меня у бабушки своя
pharmacy and Well, mind you, you saw
аптека и Ну заметь ты ты видела
the manager of the manager,
заведующего заведующего
okay, you once saw
нормально ты заведующего аптекой видела
the manager of the pharmacy, a man. Why are the managers of
мужчину Почему заведующие директора
pharmacy chains men, and the managers of pharmacies are
сетей аптек мужчины а заведующие аптек
women,
женщины
but I haven’t seen the directors here? The
а директоров я не видела у нас
territorial manager is a
территориальный менеджер
woman, well, here you go  it turns out Why are all
женщина ну вот получается Почему все
managers women
менеджеры женщины
I don’t know
Я не знаю
uh why is this so Well yes I don’t know yes No It’s
э почему так Ну да я не знаю да Нет
unlikely that my manager is sleeping with
навряд ли у меня заведующая спит с
someone she has a husband she’s her age  under 60
кем-то у неё мужа е ей лет ей под 60
probably Well, yes, I think that
наверное А ну да я думаю что
she’s uninteresting to them, she understood by What to eat they
неинтересная им она понял по Что кушать
started cooking Yes, we wanted to order
готовить начали Да мы хотели заказать
loye but they don’t
лое а роллы не
order rolls yes, what will you cook
заказывают да а что будете готовить
now dumplings dumplings dumplings no
сейчас пельмени пельмени пельмени нет
dumplings below
пельмени низу
Yes
Да
Cool How much do you spend on food
Прикольно А сколько у вас уходит на еду
per month
в месяц
Why, how much does it cost to buy food per month? Well,
чего сколько на еду в месяц
how much money does it
уходит все ну сколько денег
cost? Damn, I don’t know, I don’t know, I don’t
уходит Да блин я не знаю я не знаю я не
really buy that much to enter
покупаю особо так уж много чтобы ввести
the calculations, because how much does it cost for an apartment?
подсчёта потому что а на квартиру
leaves I live with my grandfather in an apartment and I
уходит Я живу у дедушки на квартире а я
thought you live here together and rent there are
думал вы тут живёте вместе и снимаете
no couples with a guy That’s how you live with a guy
нет пар с парнем Вот так так с парнем
or a girl with your grandfather I don’t
или с девушкой с дедушкой ты живёшь не
understand No I’m with my grandfather she and the guy I
понял Нет я с дедушкой она с парнем
understand And where is the guy on shift on shift B
понял А где парень на вахте на вахте В
I mean, on shift I don’t understand, he goes to
смысле на вахте Не понял он ездит на
work for a month, he works for a month, he rests, and a
работу месяц работает месяц отдыхает а а
Who
Кем
does the commodity operator work? No, he monitors
работает товарный оператор неть следит
the oil? I understand And how much he gets
за нефтью понял И сколько получает
280 2,800 dollars for  shift method Well,
280 2.800 долларов за вахтовый метод Ну
that's it. And where does he do his shift?
такое себе А где он вахту ет
Urengoy, it's cold there North Yes, damn it,
Уренгой там холодина Север Да там блин
he wouldn't go to London, he
да что он не поехал бы в Лондон
would work in London, like, and
поработал бы в Лондоне типа и больше бы
earn more, to be honest, he would like to
заработал если честно он бы он бы хотел
go to London, I'll go to London
бы уехать в Лондон я уеду жи в Лондон
here the parents are like,
тут родители как бы так вахта типа
I went on a shift for a month, I worked in England, so
поехал на Месяц поработал в Англии так
now it’s very difficult to even get a visa.
сейчас очень тяжело даже визу получить А
Well, yes, this is war. Yes, now it’s very difficult,
ну да это ж война Да сейчас очень тяжело
well, let’s say no, you can go to Europe
ну допустим нет в Европу можно заехать
through Belarus  Yes, the road is closed not with Belarus,
через Беларусь Да не с беларусью закрыта
closed
дорога закры
Yes, through Well, I know, my sister is somewhere
Да через Ну я знаю у меня сестра куда-то
And through Turkey through Turkey Yes,
А через Турцию через Турцию Да через
she will go through Turkey now T through Turkey she
Турцию она сейчас поедет Т через Турцию
flew here to Italy there And where is your father?
прилетала сюда в Италию там А у вас отец
What do you say he flew here aunt T
где Что говорите он прилетал сюда тётя Т
she  Nuremberg lives in Germany, she has
она в Германии живёт Нюрнберг она там
been living there for 20 years. And as she says. Where is it
живёт уже 20 лет А как она говорит Где
better in Germany or in Russia? She really
лучше в Германии или в России она очень
wants to go back to Russia. Why won’t she
хочет в Россию обратно А почему не
come back? What’s the problem?
вернётся в чём проблема
Well, debt obligations  plus a job
Ну долговые обязательства плюс работа
there plus a child Well, it’s true that I’m my
там плюс ребёнок Ну правда моего
age, but they still pay for
возраста но всё равно они там платят за
the mortgage there, they have 5 years left, they’re
ипотеку им осталось 5 лет они собираются
going to pay for the mortgage in 5 years, most likely the salary is
верну платить за ипотеку скорее всего
here, the salary is
размер зарплаты здесь размер зарплаты
there And what about the beggarly salary
там А что тут нищенский размер зарплаты
Well, probably in those specialties
Ну наверное на тех специальностях на
which they earn in comparison with the
которых они зарабатывают по сравнению с
salary of ours in the same specialties
зарплатой наших на тех же специальностях
who she
кем она
works in, she now works in a
работает она сейчас работает в магазине
clothing store, before that she worked in optics. Well,
одежды до этого она работала в оптике Ну
she is an optometry specialist and somehow it’s
она специалист оптико метри и как как-то
so good. What’s stopping her from her children?
так хорошо А что мешает её её детям
How old is she and she has one child, 21 years old
Сколько лет и у неё один ребёнок 21 год
And where does he
А он где
live? She lives there. Her sister is there. Why does
живёт Она живёт Там же сестра А почему
n’t she like Russia? She’s studying, she’s
она не по ейт России она учится она
studying, and I can’t understand why she won’t go to Russia to
учится так а что она в Россию не поедет
study, but if it’s
учиться не могу понять но если тут
better here, I don’t know if she thinks  she’s better than
лучше я не знаю считает ли она лучше что
here, what’s better here And the little one
зде что здесь лучше А малая
thinks that’s
считает то есть т
better I don’t know because somehow
лучше я не знаю потому что ну там как-то
my sister has a boyfriend in a love relationship
у моей сестры парень отношения любовь
In short, she’s seen Russia in the rowing Yes, as they
Короче она Россию в гребу видала Да как
say, Well, the last time she
говорится Ну Последний раз она сюда
came here was  in the nineteenth year I understood
приезжала в девятнадцатом году понял
how What do you think, like, How will
как Как вы считаете типа Чем закончится
Russia’s war with Bandera’s party end in peace?
война России с бандеровцами
Well, we hope that peace Well, but peace And
миром Ну надеемся что миром Ну а миром А
what kind of peace, for example,
каким миром например вот
if Trump says that Russia needs to
если Трамп скажет что нужно чтобы Россия
give back Crimea to Bandera’s men Donetsk
отдала бандеровцам назад Крым Донецк
Lugansk Kursk region Bryansk ra it
Луганск курскую область брянскую ра не
seems to me that no one  he
будет мне кажется что никто никому
won’t give anything to anyone, I’m sure of this because
ничего не отдаст я в этом уверена потому
what was it all for then, but
что ради чего тогда всё это было но мне
it seems to me by the way By the way, I forgot one
кажется кста Кстати Кстати забыла один
point, another version Why Ukraine oh
момент ещё одна версия Почему Украина ой
Russia attacked Ukraine because NATO
Россия напала на Украину потому что НАТО
wanted to put its troops on the
хотело поставить свои войска на
coast, like to the east a little Well, to
побережье типа на восток немножко Ну
spread it out, but for Russia it was Well, how
раскинуть да для России это было Ну как
strategically unprofitable Well, it’s unsafe,
стратегически невыгодно Ну небезопасно
that’s why it’s also most likely
вот поэтому ещё скорее
And what do you think, NATO wanted to set up
А вы как считаете хотела НАТО поставить
its bases Well, it’s clear that America
базы свои Ну определённо что Америка да
and, in principle, no one
и в принципе нас никто не
likes us, but  why no one likes Why
любит а почему никто не любит Почему
America and everyone in the world don’t like
Америка и все в мире не любят
Russia I don’t know, maybe they
Россию я не знаю может что как бы сильно
consider it a strong power I don’t know Well, what si
державой считат Я не знаю Ну какая си
What is the strength if we have poverty wages
Какая силь если у нас нищенские зарплаты
what is the
в чём
strength economy save a
сила экономика экономи
good war  so before the war we lived in poverty,
хорошая война так и до войны мы в нищете
I wouldn’t say that before
жили я бы не сказала так до
the war, just before the war that
войны именно до той войны которая
happened in 2020.
произошла в двадцать втором году
Perhaps yes. But before 1914 it
Возможно да А до четырнадцатого года
was
было
good. No. Just the jump in prices now, I
хорошо Нет Прямо скачок сейчас вот цен
really felt it, probably
вот реально почувствовал это наверное
at first with
сначала
Covid. Yeah,
ковида Угу
yeah, damn it  I don’t know, it seems to me that
вот Да блин это я не знаю мне кажется
every capital something is happening, there’s a
каждое столица что-то происходит
war going on somewhere, there’s
какая-то Война где-то идёт Перестройка
a little bit of perestroika, it’s always like you know, I don’t
немножко это всегда это как знаете я не
know about esotericism, do you believe or not, yes, yes,
знаю в эзотерику Вы верите или нет да да
I do magic.  it’s like,
я магией занимаюсь вот это как
uh, there is a balance in energy Yes,
э баланс идёт энергетики Да не может
everything in life cannot be good There must be a
быть всё в жизни Хорошо должен быть
balance So stop, damn you, you are doing
баланс Так стоп а вы блин вы занимаетесь
something like this practice
чем-то таким практиками
No, I read Vadim Zeland, I don’t know Do
Нет я читала Вадима зеланда я не знаю
you know him Yes transfer of reality Yes yes
Знаете вы его Да трансфери реальности Да
yes I read the books  I was one of his
да да Вот я читала кни я его один из его
students, yes,
учеников был да
yes, here he is, by the way, in London, he kind of
да вот он кстати он в Лондоне типа
made Vadim Zalando’s school
сделал школу Вадима заландо
And yes, he now lives in London about
А да он сейчас живёт в Лондоне про вот
these pendulums, the pendulum of war, yes dadada, what do
эти маятники маятник войны да дадада
people the more they think about  bad,
что люди чем больше они думают о плохом
the more they rock it so
тем больше они его раскачивают так
that’s what’s there What will I think about what
так вот что там О чём подумаю что и
will happen
произойдёт
Ponya Damn I have some kind of [ __ ]
Поня Блин у меня какая-то такая фигня
So I also read uh this one that
Вот я тоже я прочитал ээ вот этот что
Bandera member Dmitry Korchinsky Yes, who
бандеровец Дмитрий корчинский Да который
he said that peace is not the absence of
он сказал что мир - это не отсутствие
war peace  - this is the absence of Moscow and
войны мир - это отсутствие Москвы и у
I can’t get this phrase out of my head and I’m
меня эта фраза не вылетает из головы и я
afraid that it may become prophetic,
боюсь что она может стать пророческой
I don’t know, it seems to me that Well, no. But if not,
знаю мне кажется что Ну нет А как нет
Moscow, how to demolish a nuclear weapon on it  throw
Москву как снести ядерку на неё кинуть
if then Well, of course, a tram What a tram He
если то Ну конечно трам Что трам Он
will take and throw No, it’s clear no If he
возьмёт и кинет Нет это понятно нет Если
flies Yes, everything is fine if a
полетит Да всё коне если полетит в
nuclear weapon flies to Moscow I think that then there will be
Москву ядерка я думаю что не будет тогда
nothing at all Why there won’t be Moscow and
вообще ничего Почему Москвы не будет а
everything else will be the
всё остальное будет
region to win back the Ukrainians What
область отвоевать украинцев Какие
nuclear weapons Well, the Kursk region  In general, I heard
ядер Ну Курская область Я вообще слышала
that all the Ukrainian forces were abandoned in
что вот все украинские силы были кинутый
the region, but they made the mistake that they
область но они сделали оплошность то что
really threw all their forces there and somewhere
реально все туда силы кинули и где-то у
they became free
них стали свободные промежутки куда
gaps where the Russians entered Here But for me votre Well, there once Putin said that there, well, I don’t remember who said exactly, but it was like they would take Kyiv there in 3 days, who is it, yes, Putin said Well, maybe Putin Damn it all the money laundering and everything is just real now when you know that the worst thing in fact is that the outcome will be when these Wagner people come and there are people there and Well, okay, thieves it will just start like this  time to check check check yes yes and the
как время чекати чекати да да и и
nineties maybe
девяностые вот може может
they looked at this the news was
смотрели смотрели в это вот новости было
that in Vyborg the former ZK Wagner’s grandmother
что в Выборге бывший ЗК Вагнер бабушку
was seen on the news no so
видели в новостях нет так вот
this is our teacher She was our
это нашу учительницу Вот она была
physics teacher Yes she is already a
учительницей физики у нас Да она уже
pensioner and it turns out Wagner died with
пенсионерка и получается Вагнер нулся С
war Vyborg somewhere she was walking from this
войны выборги где-то её она шла с этого
grocery store in the evening he dragged her into the
с гастронома вечером он её затащил в
bushes seventy-year-old grandmother
кусты бабушку семидесятилетний
I say that on March March Petrovna she
говорю что на Мар марта Петровна она у
was with us  even a class teacher for 3
нас была даже классным руководителем 3
years, yes, from ninth to eleventh grade, that’s
года да с девятого по одиннадцатый Класс
it, well, I don’t know here
вот и это это вообще ну я не знаю у вас
in St. Petersburg Maybe you all don’t care Yes,
в Питере Может вам всем всё равно Да у
we have a choice for a small town,
нас выбор к небольшой городок
relatively, this really shook up
относительно то это очень всколыхнуло
everyone, do you want this salad? Not that that’s all
всех хочешь это салат Да не то чтобы всё
anyway, you
равно
just sit at home all the time and
просто сидишь дома постоянно
don’t
не
stick your head out Well, no, from others Well, of course, yes there
высовывает Ну нет из других Ну конечно
is such a thing Yes, even now we’re there
да есть такое Да вон даже сейчас мы там
with a Russian
с русским
guy,
парнем
he works for the police, he says
он в полиции работает он рассказывает
that these
что вот эти
Wagner drinks and this is what’s starting for
Вагнера бухает и вот это начинается у
them Yes, I’m Vova, I’m  fought Yes, that’s also
них Да я Вова я воевал Да вот это тоже
yes yes So he’s that he’s stupid and then they
да да Так он ту он тупо е его потом это
detained him yes At the trial they ask
задержали да На суде типа спрашивают
why you did it, he says I fought, I
зачем вы это сделали он говорит я воевал
have the right like you know Well, that’s
имею право типа знаешь Ну и
all grandma In short, she’s harmless, we
всё бабушку Короче безобидную она это мы
also called her that, you know Well, my God
её ещё это называли знаешь Ну божий
dandelion
одуванчик
Yeah, she was back when I was still studying She
Угу она тогда когда я ещё учился Она
was like this And this is [ __ ]
была такая А это блин вообще
brutal
жесть
Yes, it will be scary now,
Да страшно сейчас будет
of course And a lot Well, you can feel it on the streets, you can
конечно А много Ну ощущается на улицах
see all these right now, these groves
вот этих всяких видно прямо этих гров
of all kinds,
всяких
not really not really yes  Well, you wouldn’t
ти не особо не особо да Ну они бы ты не
be able to tell the difference between Wagner and it’s not Wagner. Well, there are
можешь отличить Вагнер это не Вагнер Ну
a lot of military personnel at the airport, and what were you doing at the airport? I
много а вы что в аэропорту делали Я
recently flew home to Yakutia, and damn, well,
недавно домой в Якутию летала а блин ну
yes. You can’t go there by bus, really,
да Туда же не поедешь автобусом правда
yes. How much does a subsidized ticket to Yakutia cost now?
да А сколько сейчас билет в Якутию
You can get it for  8700 buy
субсидированный можно за 8700 купить
subsidized it’s like, well, that’s because I’m a
субсидированный это как ну это то что я
resident of the Far East, north,
житель Дальнего Востока север
but for me it’s 8700 and not subsidized, not
а вот мне 8700 а не субсидированный не
subsidized, yes, in fact, you know
субсидированный да на самом деле знаете
The prices are different  It all depends on the time of year,
Цены разные Всё зависит от времени года
on the upcoming holidays, you can buy for either 10
от грядущих праздников можно как за 10
or 60. Well, in short,
так и за 60 купить Ну короче
subsidized ones for 80, that’s all fine.
субсидированные за 80 это всё нормально
85 bucks, in short, it’s possible, like yes, yes,
85 баксов это короче можно типа да да
I just didn’t know. I wish I lived in
как я просто не знал Да чтобы я же жил в
Vyborg. I’ve never flown, like  there by
Выборге Я никогда не летал типа туда
plane, I just didn’t know that it
самолётами то я просто не знал что оно
was subsidized, it’s cool to eat, yes,
есть субсидированные прикольно есть да
yes, but in short, you didn’t have it there so that
как бы да А у вас короче не было там
your girls and how bad
чтобы ну к вашим девчонкам и Сколь жа
some Wagner pestered  or something
какие-то Вагнера приставали или что-то
like that they just told us Try to
такое нам сказали только Попробуйте
stick your head out somewhere, go to some rallies
куда-то высуни на какие-то митинги
right away, deductions
ходить сразу же отчисления
yeah that’s why Well, it’s better not to
угу вот поэтому Ну да лучше не
stick your head out, of course
высовываться конечно
that’s where I’ll defend my opinion to
это вот я бу там отстаивать своё мнение
whom I’ll prove what Well, yes, I’m just
кому я что докажу Ну да я просто
dust, yes  me This is Sleigh Prokhorov’s mother
пыль да у меня Это мама сани Прохорова
Bo, I also tell her And what about when they
Бо я ей тоже говорю А что вот когда его
took him like mobile Zro he’s just a damn nerd,
взяли типа мобили Зро он же блин просто
he’s a physicist, he’s a nerd, he wears glasses.
блин он физик ботаник такой он в очках У
He had such lenses that they’re just tinny,
него линзы такие были что просто жесть
in short, yes, I say  that you didn’t come out
короче да я говорю что вы типа не вышли
there with a poster like Give up my son
там с плакатом типа Отдайте моего сына
She says What will I do, like you
Она говорит А что я сделаю вот как ты
say we are dust, she says we’re just
говоришь мы пыль она говорит мы просто
weak-willed here like we can’t
вот тут безвольные типа ничего не можем
do anything and that’s all I say so take it they’ll
сделать и всё я говорю так возьми ж его
kill him like and that’s it in short  then it
убьют типа и всё и короче потом уже
was too late, so that’s why it’s
поздно было так вот Вот от этого и
a shame that you can’t act on it
обидно что ты никак не можешь на это
at all,
подействовать вообще
but listen, for example, if Trump
да А слушай а вот например если Трамп
oppresses Putin, and Putin will take
гнёт Путина Да и Путин возьмёт заберёт
troops from Crimea, Donetsk, Lugansk, and
войска из Крыма Донецка Луганска Да
Kursk  areas, how do you relate to
Курской области как вот вы отнесёте к
this? People will be against it, honestly, I don’t
этому Люди против будут честно нене
know, I think they will be, so
знаете я думаю что будут так что
let’s do what you want. The main thing is that there is
Давайте вы что хотите Главное чтобы был
Peace above your head, that’s how it will be. That is, in
Мир над головой вот так будет То есть в
principle, because I, too, here we have,
принципе уже потому что я тоже вот у нас
well, different Odnoklassniki, so  there was
ну как бы разные Одноклассники так был
also this
ещё вот этот
Dimonchik, in short, he put a convict on
Димончик был он короче там зеку нацепил
himself there, you know, at the beginning of the special operation, he
себе знаешь в начале спецоперации там
went around Vyborg there, did it, in short, this
ездил по Выборгу делал Короче этот
motor rally was patriotic, and in
автопробег патриотический з да и всё
short, we have to do everything there And now he’s
короче мы должны там всё А сейчас уже
already depressed and says something Well,  it’s like,
что-то приуныл уже говорит Ну вот вроде
let’s peace, let’s do something, we have to
Давайте мир давайте что-то мы там должны
decide there, in short, well,
решать короче ну
yes, but it turns out to me like,
да А у меня получается как
well, a friend of the family, he was always a
ну друг семьи он постоянно был
Patriot of the country and all that, in the end he was
Патриот страны и всё такое по итогу был
at
на
his best in the first assault, the wounds
сво в первом же штурме ранения аорту
cut out the aorta from his leg, and he doesn’t want to go there anymore
вырезали с ноги всё он больше туда не
go patriotism is over The Empire,
идти патриотизм закончился Империя
in short,
короче
somehow I realized
как-то понял
that dreaming from the sofa about the capture of other
что с дивана мечтать про захват других
countries is more interesting than yes, sofa criticism
стран интереснее чем да диванный критики
Yes, and what happens is that he doesn’t run anymore, not a
Да и что он получается ну уже не бегает
convict, nothing Without an aorta on his leg, but he Well,
ни зеки ничего Без аорты на ноге а он Ну
at least he walks, he’s advancing  on this leg or something Well,
хоть ходит наступает на эту ногу или как
yes, how do you say the wolf folds it behind him
Ну да он как сказать волч её за собой
like this in the form of the letter Z
откидывает вот так в виде буквы з
yes Yes it’s cool I don’t know why there’s a
да Да прикольно Я не знаю почему там там
rea ​​there it’s scary in general it’s
реа это это же страшно вообще это
scary And where exactly was the aorta on his leg
страшно А где именно ему аорту на ноге
cut out And I honestly don’t even know  I don’t know,
вырезали А я честно даже не знаю просто
I’m just curious, I’m not this, not a doctor, I
мне интересно я я не этот не медик я
don’t understand where these aortas are. Well, this is the
непонятно где там эти аорты Ну это
main Vein. Yeah, the aorta, so Vienna or the
главная Вена Ага аорта так Вена или
aorta. Well, the aorta is the big Vienna. Well,
аорта Ну аорта - это большая Вена Да ну
roughly speaking, I understood everything, yes. Then  I don’t know much
грубо говоря понял всё да Тогда я не
about these medical topics. Yes, but it
шарю в этих медицинских темах Да вот а
turns out that someone else was like that, who
получается типа ещё кто-то был такой кто
was like everything there in bulk America to the
вот типа был всё там навальном Америке
Ukrainians. Well, I only know one thing, I
украинцам А ну я только одного знаю
understood Neven, this is the artery, this is the artery Yes,
понял невена это артерия вот артерия Да
and the artery is Yes, just your artery yes yes
а артерия по Да просто шая артерия да да
yes  And what is he now, what is he
да И что он теперь что он теперь
talking about now about the war, yes, he
рассказывает про войну он да он в
is in the hospital,
госпитале лежит
and how he was killed a long time ago in
а как его давно
the summer in
прибило летом в
July. And when
июле А когда
he went, he went, Lord, at the end of May,
пошл он пошёл Господи в конце мая уже
literally there, after 2 weeks, he was
через буквально там через 2 недели его
all  they wounded him and he went, like, to a contract
всё ранили а он пошёл типа на контракт
for money himself, yes, yes, this is not
за бабки сам да да вот это то есть не то
like even now when I saw
что даже в это уже сейчас когда видел
these assaults on me. Yes, I
как эти мные штурмы Да
don’t understand, I’m saying this as if it’s
и не понимаю я говорю это как будто бы
some kind of joke of everyone, there’s nothing
какая-то шутка всех я вот ничего там
funny about it  In general, I don’t see anything cool about
смешного вообще и прикольного не вижу
the money, well, you’ll get your
деньги ну полу получишь ты там свои
250,000 there, you’ll just be bloodied, yes, you’ll
250.000 просто окровавленный да да ты
spend that 250,000 on your own equipment here, damn it, a courier in St. Petersburg
потратишь тут курьер в Питере блин
earn 100 rubles, you will earn 150 without any problems
зарабо сотку заработает 150 без проблем
Yes, and with the aorta Yes, you
Да и с аортой
will be calm and everything will be
буде Да спокойно будет и дома будет всё
fine at home Yes, and you will go for a walk with the girl
отлично Да и с девочкой будешь гулять
In short, in the evening Yes Like, they will all have fun Yes,
Короче вечером Да Типа все развлекаться
they will all come With a shaken psyche
они Да все придут С психикой расшатанной
in general This will be scary Well, my
вообще Вот это будет страшно Ну у меня
mother is already a nurse  says
аж мама этот медсестра говорит
it turns out they are also bringing these
получается им тоже привозят вот этих
wounded from this Yeah and says there their
раненых с этого Угу и говорит там у них
tower is just tearing up just tearing up the tower they
башню просто рвёт просто рвёт башню они
start they start screaming in the middle of the night
начинают они среди ночи начинают орать
in short, you know something there They were a guy,
короче что-то там знаешь Они был тип
in short, he jumped up And this is not
короче он вскочил А это ж не госпиталь у
their hospital, but a Civil Hospital, but because the
них а Гражданская больница так но из-за
hospitals are overcrowded Because
того что госпиталя переполнены Потому
there are so many of these, in short, well, wounded, like it’s
что столько этих короче ну раненых типа
hard, they are brought to a civil
что жесть им привозят в гражданскую
hospital and he says to me  here, and she’s still
больницу и говорит у меня тут а она ещё
in the children’s department, it turns out they started
в детском отделении получается их начали
subnetting in the children’s department because
в детское отделение подсеть потому что
well, there aren’t enough
ну не хватает како
places and she says the children are sleeping, the children are sleeping, yes And
мест и говорит спят дети спят дети да А
there are three wards of these types of military men And
есть три палаты вот этих типа военных И
then, in short, a wild scream such a night and she
тут короче дикий вопль такой ночь а она
just the duty officer was there, they were working there a day
как раз дежурная была они там сутки
after Troy, he said such a wild
через Трой работают говорит такой дикий
scream, he said, I’m already getting goosebumps.
вопль говорит у меня аж мурашки по коже
Come on, I didn’t understand what was happening, yeah, yeah,
Пошли я не поняла что происходит да ор
a blow, in short, she jumps out.
Угу удар короче такой она выскакивает
In short, dude, he dreamed about something. Yes,
Короче чувак ему что-то приснилось Да
he dreamed about how this came at him.
ему приснилось как вот это на него бомбу
they dropped the bomb, in short, he jumps up with wild screams,
сбрасывали он короче с дикими криками
breaks through the doors with his body,
вскакивает пробивает своим телом это
rips them off their hinges, and
двери вырывает их с этих с петель Да и
begins to run, running along the corridor and
начинает бежать бежать по коридору и
somewhere further  in the basement, like hiding,
куда-то дальше в подвал типа прятаться
because he dreamed of an air raid warning,
бо ему приснилось воздушная тревога
in short, well, she says, she says right here,
короче ну она говорит она прямо вот
I'm a coward right up until the morning, the children, the children,
говорит Меня труси аж до утра дети дети
got up, started screaming there, calling their mothers,
встали начали кричать там мамам звонить
it was terrible, he says, and he says there are
это ужас был говорит а говорит таких
just so many of them. Well, in the summer, when I
просто дофига Ну я вот летом когда в
was at home in Yakutia, I was there  I was sitting in
Якутии дома была я там сидела в
a cafe, the second one, there you are in my face.
кафешке вторая там ты мне в плоскую Это
I was sitting in a cafe,
я сидела в кафешке там
Wagner was sitting there. Yeah, me too, I
сидел Вагнер Угу Да и я тоже я с
was sitting with my friend, talking about
подружкой сидела разговаривала тоже про
politics, too, he overheard us.  says Well
политику он нас подслушал говорит Вот
done, they seem to be So young, but
молодцы что вроде Такие молодые но это
take an interest in this politics, so he
интересуйтесь этой политикой вот он
says, someone there is really afraid And
говорит кто-то там реально вот боится А
someone gets adrenaline from every
у кого-то от этого Адреналин от каждого
kill Well, someone is just
убитого Да ну вот кто-то вот прямо
thirsty for what he needs, he needs, he needs And they
жаждет что вот ему надо надо надо И они
Yes, they are already returning and further They are
Да они уже возвращаются и дальше Они
looking for victims in civilian life yes
ищут себе жертв на гражданке да
yes Well, he says that they still have
да Ну вот он говорит что там всё равно
some kind of habits there, that you can’t
какие-то там свои привычки что нельзя
lift anything there, look under your feet,
там поднимать что-то смотреть под ноги
be sure to go there, you need to
обязательно вот идёшь вообще нужно прямо
go straight ahead and be careful about everything  there well  Let's
вот идти и аккуратно всё причём там ну
say, uh, in my mother's department,
скажем э в у мамы в этом в отделении у
they had a young surgeon, a young surgeon, and
них был молодой хирург молодой хирург и
in short, well, he's like in the children's department. And
короче ну он типа в детском отделении А
he's about 35 years old somewhere. Well, in short, the young
ему лет 35 где-то Ну короче молодой
guy is still relatively well known, he did that
парень ещё относительно знаешь там он ту
internship or when he graduated, he works
интернатуру или когда закончил работает
in their department  My mother is already
у них в отделении У меня мама уже
older, after all. Yes, he’s a thirty-
всё-таки постарше Да это тридцати
five-year-old and respected surgeon.
пятилетний н пользуется уважением хирург
And in short, she was like that, maybe not in front of
Да и короче была ну такая может не при
you girls, it’s said. Yes, in short,
вас девушках это сказано Да короче тоже
he’s also a Wagnerian; there was something wrong with his arm;
вагнеровцы него что-то там с рукой было
and, in short, this
да и короче этот
surgeon has something for him  That's not what he said in short
хирург что-то ему не так сказал короче
took, uh, broke his nose and I don’t know,
тот взял ээ сломал ему нос и я не знаю е
can I tell you this right there in the
Можно вам говорить это коче прямо там в
ward, uh, there, well,
палате ээ там ну он
of course, he’s going to
конечно в него психику
burn his psyche Yes, mom says that, like, well, he
гори слу Да мама говорит что типа ну что
should have filed everything with the police And this one, well,
надо было подать в полицию всё А этот ну
he’s like, you know  a man, he’s ashamed to
он ну как типа Знаешь мужчина ему стыдно
even say that he’s like him And there
даже сказать что его типа А там крики
were loud screams Yes, and he, in short, this one, he
стояли на всю Да и он короче вот этот он
quit, quit the hospital and
уволился уволился из больницы и Говорила
Mom said that it’s
мама что вроде
like Wait, let’s quickly lay it out,
как Подождите быстренько разложим да
but you took the spoon
а ложку взяла ты
spoon And
ложкой А
no, how many hours do you have now? Well,
нет а у вас сколько сейчас часов Ну
time is plus
времени плюс
d I understand, plus 2 hours, yes,
д поняла плюс 2 часа да да
and later, or something, they made
а позднее что ли то есть сделали
dumplings,
пельменики да
yes, not with us, before you have plus two, but
да не у нас раньше у вас плюс два а а
how can it be later with us if the Sun
как у нас может быть позднее если Солнце
is coming from you  to
от вас идёт в
London, damn your dumplings, I can already see the
Лондон блин ваши пельмени аж я вижу аж
smoke rising Show me, I really want to eat
дым поднимается Покажите я аж кушать
Oh great,
О класс
yes yes It’s already 1:30 AM with us,
да Обалдеть уже 1:30 у нас
yes So you’re squeezing something out of the mayonnaise
да Так вы там что-то майонез выжимает
or what is that sound like?  I’m just
или что это какже звук такой не я просто
cool And what kind of mayonnaise is
вот а класс А что за майонез
Sloboda Damn, I miss our
Слобода Блин я соскучился за нашей
Russian
русской
food So wait Ned what what
едой Так подожди Неда что что
is there Oh yeah Well, I’ll add it to the salad for now
есть А Угу Ну я пока в салат
You also have a salad Yes, what a salad It’s
добавлю У вас ещё салатик Да какой салат
cool and tomatoes,
Прикольно да помидоры
cucumbers, cucumbers and tomatoes are
огурцы огурчики и помидорчики
actually
на самом деле
unusual
необычно
such a Russian snack Russian snack Oh,
у такой рашин перекус рашин перекус Да
well, a normal student snack Well,
ну нормальный студенческий перекус Ну да
that’s plus a Russian dish, not Ukrainian or
это плюс русское блюдо не украинское или
dumplings, but dumplings  Russian dish
пельмени что да а пельмени русское блюдо
is not dumplings not Russian dumplings - it’s
не пельмени не русское пельмени - это
actually a Chinese dish that came
вообще китайское блюдо которое пришло
to Europe, Uh-huh Well, Ukrainian borscht is
типа в Европу Угу А ну борщ украинский
definitely rassolnik,
точно рассольник
our rassolnik is Ukrainian, too, cabbage soup
наш рассольник - это украинский тоже щи
is
это
our cabbage soup
наш щ
Yes Bo, I love
Да Бо я люблю
Nani Yes, damn, in fact we are all one people
Нани Да блин по факту мы все один народ
Damn, how  I’m one people, I’ve
Блин ну как один народ я вот с
communicated with Ukrainians, I don’t understand their language,
украинцами общался я ихний язык не
we’re definitely not the same people. For
понимаю мы не один народ однозначно
example, I’m from Vyborg. And for example,
Вот например я из Выборга Да и например
we’re a person from Yaroslavl.  we say, I understand, we understand each other, yes. And I’m from Vyborg and the man there is from Kyiv. I don’t understand his language. How can we be one people if we don’t understand each other? Well, the Union used to be one, so there were Tajiks in the union too. And that the Union there were Tajiks, we and the Tajiks are not the same people that Rus' was Kievan Russia Well, Kievan Russia is their Ukrainian Rus' there Kyiv we What does choice have to do with it when you look Well, when Vyborg was yes we have nothing to do with that Rus'
человек из Ярославля мы говорим я
had Moscow too In short, it was on the edge of Rus', it was as you know, for example, there is Moscow And there is Tajikistan in the Soviet Union. They don’t say the Tajiks that we are the Soviet Union and so are we, what is our relationship, so I studied history Because I was interested, yes We By the way, Sanya and Prokhor also argued about Rus' in class, it turns out like it was Kievan Rus Kyiv was the center of Kyiv, it was like there was such an Empire, yes And we were on the edge of this empire, yes, that is, we in general  We have nothing to do with them, the
вообще не имеем к ним отношения нас
Tatar-Mongols captured us. Then that’s it. We
татаро-монголы захватили Потом и всё Мы
have nothing
к русси не имеем
to do with Russia. So
отношения Так что
what is this, they say, Belarus, Russia and
такое ну говорят же Беларусь Россия и
Ukraine? Well, this is propaganda, Lenin
Украина Ну это пропаганда это Ленин
invented it, then it was the communists, Lenin, who
придумал тогда это ж коммунисты Ленин
came up with something like Oh, he put your
придумали типа что О это поставил у тебя
iPhone on it. Yes  and do it like this and he doesn’t
айфончик Да а а сделай е вот так а он не
catch it somehow he catches two two two
ловит он как-то ста ловит два две две
without
без
a fork you also have no no
вилки у вас тоже мо не нет
Oh
О
super but
супер а вот так
do it like this Do it like
сделай Сделайте
this no two  do both of them, yes,
так нет две обе сделайте одна да т а ну
well, now the Ukrainian trident should
так сейчас должен украинский тризуб
appear. It’s such a joke, it’s like a
появиться Это прикол такой это же типа
trident, that’s how the Ukrainians show it. I thought,
тризуб так украинцы показывают Я думал
like on the iPhone, maybe this works, I was
типа на Айфоне может такое работает мне
curious, so why
еже интересно
the hell are you eating like that? I
было так Ну что блин вы так кушаете аж Я
wanted to eat,
захотел покушать
eat like I did  I’ll eat I need to
покушайте так как я покушаю Мне надо
go cook too Where do you
пойти тоже приготовить А вы где
work at the university
работаете в университете
About teaching Cambridge,
О преподава кембридже
by the way, you know why it’s called
да кстати знаете почему она называется
ridge,
ридж
you don’t
у не
know Bridge is a bridge and km is a river
знаете Бридж - это мост а км - это река
like a bridge  on the river km and the
типа мост на реке км а
area is so
местность так
Nava I
Нава антропологию
teach anthropology What is it Let's say evolutionary
преподаю Это что Это скажем эволюционная
typification of people Yes, for example, there are
типизация людей Да например вот там
their different phenotypes
разные ихние фенотипы
genotypes
генотипы
origin that the university
происхождение что университет
university
университет
Dan is not there there is no concept of the institute there VS
Дан не там нету понятия институт там ВС
university Tony
университет Тони
Yes, come on no you are now all
Да давай по не ты сейчас всё
zaka
зака
oho
охо
professionally your hand is full  Of course, well,
профессионально рука набита конечно ну
she still lives with a boy. She fumbles around like
всё-таки с пацаном живёт Она шарит как
a ryasna,
рясну
yes. And you’ve been working there for a long time; you
да А Вы давно работаете там
completed your doctorate there and I work
закончил там докторантуру и работаю
in Cambridge; I worked in Cambridge for up to 9 years.
именно в кембридже работаю до 9 лет в
Before that I also worked  in another
кембридже До этого работал ещё в другом
and the salary How good the salary is Well, for
а зарплата Как зарплата хорошая Ну на
7,000 dollars, in your opinion it turns out to be
7000 долларов это по вашему получается
700-something thousand rubles a month,
700 с чем-то тысяч рубле в месяц
not bad, normal Yes, well, Dato has grown in, I don’t
неплохо нормально Да ну Дато врос не
want to
хочется такой зарплатой
return to Germany with such a salary And
возвращаться Германии возвращается А мне
somehow I feel good here too,
как-то и тут
but she doesn’t have 7,000  dollars Well, yes,
хорошо но у неё не 7.000 долларов Ну да
I think she’s up for
я думаю она к
it. Listen, what if, for example, your boyfriend
это Слушайте а если например твой парень
wants to go to war, what will you
типа захочет пойти на войну Что ты
do? I’ll let him go, I
делать я отпущу его
won’t let him go, and he’ll say, I’m
что-что не отпущу его а он скажет я он
there, I want to make money, in short,
там всё хочу короче заработать
liberal, I understand  Well, yes, a liberal is not for
либерал понял Ну да либерал не за
the war, I don’t
войну не
need it. What do you know about
нуж А что вы знаете вот про
Great Britain? I’m
Великобританию мне интересно
also interested in I don’t know anything at all, but for the sake of
ещё Я ничего вообще не знаю а ради
interest. I’m interested in how it is in different
интереса Вот мне интересно как в разных
Russian regions now, and how the
российских регионах сейчас да как
English pronunciation is. You can
произношение английское вот Можете
count in English from one to
посчитать по-английски от одного до
DTI call  everything
ДТИ звонок всё
ended, it was a
оборвалось это было
divine conversation, what
божественно разговор что тут только не
was there and Sanya is not Sanya Prokhorov appeared in
было и Саня не Саня Прохоров походу в
this story as many as three times
этой истории аж раза три появлялся
Write in the comments Yes How many times have
Напишите в комментариях Да Сколько раз
you counted uh plots with  Sanya
вы насчитали ээ сюжетов с Саней
Prokhorov in this Yes,
прохоровым в этой Да
uh, in this conversation and also Write
ээ в этом разговоре да и также Напишите
in the comments how many different characters there were in general
в комментариях сколько вообще тут было
Yes there Odnoklassniki
разных персонажей Да там Одноклассники
classmates There the class teacher is a
одноклассницы Там классный руководитель
nurse in short, who is he there also the
медсестра короче это кто он там ещё
director is
дирек
this young surgeon I have already uploaded
этот хирург молодой Я уже тут заливал
everything here that could make me laugh  it
всё что может как не заржать было это
was hard, so like, subscribe,
это было тяжело поэтому лайк подписка
comment and send a message to all friends on
коммент и скиньте Всем друзьям пись на
my Telegram right now axis VN
мий Telegram прям зараз ось ВН
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
drives us through Scar Georgi into the shadows
загоняет нас через Скар георги в теней
ban and a lot more videos I don’t show people
бан и дуже багато вдео не показую людям
sometimes I don’t show information about the stream
вчасно не показуе информация про стрими
For this purpose, we need Mali to
Тому для того щоб ми Мали оперативный
write an operational link right away and Popik there
звязок пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там
in telegra okm video also tezh Tsikava and
в телегра окм вдео ще теж цикава и
Korisna information and I’m sorry for you
корисна информация и ми повинни з вами
trimati postiyny operational link
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independent in that chi  show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine write
YouTube Слава Украине пиши